(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
答えて ねぇ
Answer me, hey
にわか雨がよせる
To the city where a passing shower...
街の夜へ
...approaches at night
沈む世界 感覚遡行
The sinking world, a regression of senses
「きっと僕ら生まれながら
"We are surely, since birth,
何処にもないコタエを探してる」
searching for a non-existent answer"
真っ赤な夕空
A bright red evening sky
青くなる星
A star turning blue
心臓を焦がして
Scorching my heart
冷めない温度
A temperature that won't cool
半端に零した声の残響と
With the echo of a voice half-uttered
半端に混ざった花の色
And the colors of flowers half-mixed
立ち止まって芽を育てても
Even if I stop and nurture the buds
きっと咲いた瞬間に散ってしまう
They'll surely scatter the moment they bloom
薄れてしまった記憶を抱えて
Holding onto memories that have faded away
光の影にあなたを探す
I search for you in the shadows of the light
まるで鏡合わせのような
As if we were reflections in a mirror
偽物だらけの世界でも
Even in a world full of fakes
あなたが笑ってくれるなら
If only you would smile for me
それだけで良かったのに
That alone would have been enough
擦り切れてしまった言葉を
The words that have been worn out
拾い集めては閉じ込めた
I gathered them up and locked them away
届かない声が空に溶けて
The voice that won't reach melts into the sky
夜を越えて 朝を待つ
Passing through the night, waiting for the morning
真っ赤な夕空青くなる星
A bright red evening sky, a star turning blue
心臓を焦がして冷めない温度
Scorching my heart, a temperature that won't cool
半端に零した声の残響と
With the echo of a voice half-uttered
半端に混ざった花の色
And the colors of flowers half-mixed
立ち止まって芽を育てても
Even if I stop and nurture the buds
きっと咲いた瞬間に散ってしまう
They'll surely scatter the moment they bloom
薄れてしまった記憶を抱えて
Holding onto memories that have faded away
光の影にあなたを探す
I search for you in the shadows of the light
さよならは言わないよ
I won't say goodbye
いつかまた会えるその日まで
Until the day we can meet again
この歌をあなたに届けるよ
I'll deliver this song to you
忘れないでいてね
Please don't forget me
紫咲シオン 卒業LIVE
Murasaki Shion Graduation LIVE
今宵も頭上では
Even tonight, above my head
綺麗な満月がキラキラ
The beautiful full moon is sparkling
幸せそうに世界を
Illuminating the world
照らしている
that seems to be happy
どの私も
What about me?
出来損ないでどうしようもなくて
I can't even do that right, and I'm at a loss
夜明け夢見ては
While dreaming of the dawn...
地べた這いずり回ってる
I'm dragging my feet on the ground
それでも誰かに
Still, I want someone...
見つけてほしくて
to find me
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
Looking up at the night sky and shouting
逃げ出したいなあ
I want to escape...
逃げ出せない
but I can't escape
明るい未来は見えないね
I can't see a bright future, can I?
それでもあなたに
Still, I want you...
見つけてほしくて
to find me
蝶のように
Soaring like a butterfly...
舞い上がるの
I'll dance high
欠けた翼で飛んだ
Flying with broken wings...
醜い星の子ミカヅキ
the ugly star child 'Mikazuki'
今宵も頭上では
Tonight as well, above my head,
綺麗な満月がゆらゆら
the beautiful full moon wavers.
誰かの腕に抱かれて
Held in someone's arms,
眠っている
they are sleeping.
当の私は
As for me,
独りの夜に押し潰されては
I'm being crushed by the lonely night,
誰にも見えない
unseen by anyone,
夜闇這いずり回ってる
crawling around in the darkness of night.
それでも誰にも負けたくなくて
Even so, I don't want to lose to anyone,
宇宙の隅で藻掻いている
struggling in a corner of the universe.
追い付きたいや
I want to catch up,
追い越したい
I want to overtake.
あぁ 夢に見たような世界
Ah, a world like the one in my dreams.
それでも誰かと比べてばっか
Even so, I'm always comparing myself with others,
周りを見ては立ち止まって
looking around and coming to a standstill,
欠けたものを探した
I searched for what was missing.
そんな自分を
I want to change
変えたい
that self.
それでもあなたと
Even so, because I want
おんなじ景色が
to see the same scenery
また見たいから
with you again,
泣き出したくても
even if I want to cry,
投げ出したくても
even if I want to throw it away,
諦めたりはできない
I cannot give up.
それでもあなたに
Even so, so that you
見つかるように
can find me,
サナギは強く
the chrysalis strongly
手を伸ばすの
reaches out its hand.
欠けたもの抱きしめて
Embracing what's missing,
願いを放つよ
I release my wish,
ミカヅキ
Mikazuki.
それでも誰かに
Even so, I want someone
見つけて欲しくて
to find me,
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
looking up at the night sky and screaming.
泣き出したいけど
I want to cry,
泣き出さない
but I won't cry,
もう後戻りなどできないね
I can't turn back anymore, can I?
それでもあなたに
Even so, I want
見つけて欲しくて
you to find me,
蝶のように舞い上がるの
I will soar like a butterfly.
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ
I'll fly with these broken wings,
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
ugly child of the stars, Mikazuki.
光を放った ミカヅキ
Releasing light, Mikazuki.
今宵も頭上では
Tonight as well, above my head,
綺麗な満月がキラキラ
the beautiful full moon sparkles,
次は君の番だと
laughing and saying,
笑っている
'It's your turn next.'
「こんな世界」と嘆くだれかの
Could I become the reason to live
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
for someone lamenting 'such a world'?
これは僕が いま君に贈る
This is the first and last word of love
最初で最期の愛の言葉だ
I send to you now.
街も人も歪み出した
The city and people began to warp;
化け物だと気付いたんだ
I realized they were monsters.
欲動に巣食った愚かさも
Even the foolishness nesting in desires,
すべてがこの目に映る
everything is reflected in these eyes.
シアトリカルに手の上で
Theatrically, upon the palm,
誰も彼も踊らされる
everyone is made to dance.
生まれた意味だって知らぬまま
Without even knowing the meaning of birth,
形骸化した夢は錆び付いてしまった
hollowed-out dreams have rusted away.
愛をください
Give me love.
きっと誰もがそうだった
Surely everyone was like that.
愛をください
Give me love.
そっと震えた手を取って
Gently taking the trembling hand.
愛をください
Give me love.
心を抉る
Gouging out the heart,
醜いくらいに美しい愛を
a love so beautiful it's almost ugly.
こんな世界と嘆くだれかの
Could I become the reason to live
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
for someone lamenting 'such a world'?
いつか終わると気付いたから
Because I realized it will end someday,
シアトリカルに鳴らせ心臓を
theatrically make the heart sound.
ねぇ このまま夢に溺れて
Hey, if I could just drown in a dream
愛に溶けていけたら 構わないから
and melt into love, I wouldn't mind.
どうか、どうか、またあの日と同じように
Please, please, just like that day,
傘を...
the umbrella...
もしも夢が覚めなければ
If only I never woke from this dream
姿変えずにいられた
I could have stayed in that form
ほどけた指から消える温度
The warmth vanishing from our unclasped fingers
血を巡らせるのはだれの想いで
Whose feelings are making my blood circulate?
雨に濡れた肺 縋りついた秒 昏んだ装丁電灯
Lungs soaked by rain, seconds clung to, dark streetlights
夕暮れ飛ばして止まったままの観覧車
Skipping the twilight, the Ferris wheel stays still
机に咲く花 君の声もなにもかも
The flowers on the desk, your voice, and everything else
最初からなかったみたいだ
It's as if they never existed from the start
死体 僕は今日も息をして
Like a corpse, I still breathe today
生きたい 君は明日を見失って
While you, wanting to live, lost sight of tomorrow
なのにどうして悲しいのだろう
So why does it feel so sad?
息苦しくするのが人間だ
Making things suffocating is what humans do
「あぁ」なんて嘆いたけど
Although I lamented with an "Ah..."
思い通りの日々じゃないけど
It wasn't the days I hoped for
脆く弱い糸に繋がれた
But I'm tied by fragile, weak threads
次の夜明けがまた訪れる
The next dawn will come again
どんな世界も君がいるなら
If you are here, in any world
生きていたいって思えたんだよ
I thought I'd want to live
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my hell, you are always...
絶えず鼓動する心臓だ
...the heart that's beating without end
いつしか君がくれたように
Just as you gave to me one day
僕も、だれかの心臓になれたなら
If I too, could become someone's heart
はい！というわけで
Right! And so...
お？
Oh?
え？
Eh?
なんだこれ？
What is this?
ホロライブ2期生、紫咲シオンさん。
Hololive 2nd Gen, Murasaki Shion-san.
至急校長室まで来てください。
Please come to the principal's office immediately.
えー！めんどくさい！
Ehh! So annoying!
なんで？
Why?
仕方ないですね。
I guess I have no choice.
え？
Eh?
すごーい！
Wow!
なんだこれ？ めっちゃきれい！
What's this? It's so beautiful!
すごっ！
Amazing!
シオンさん、こちらへどうぞ。
Shion-san, please come this way.
YAGOOさんだ！
It's YAGOO-san!
はい。
Yes.
卒業証書。
Graduation Certificate.
紫咲シオン。12月8日生。
Murasaki Shion. Born December 8th.
あなたは魔界学校の課程を修了しましたので、ここに証します。
You have completed the course at the Demon World School, and I hereby certify it.
令和7年4月26日。
April 26, Reiwa 7 (2025).
谷郷元昭。
Tanigo Motoaki.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
みんな見てー！
Everyone, look!
もらっちゃった！ 卒業証書！ イェーイ！
I got it! My graduation certificate! Yay!
すごーい！ すごっこれ！
Incredible! This is amazing!
ん？ え？
Hm? Eh?
なに？ なに？
What? What?
えー！まだ渡したいものがあるの？
Eh! You still have something you want to give me?
シオンさん、お疲れ様です。
Shion-san, good work.
また、配信をご視聴のファンの皆様、いつも応援ありがとうございます。
Also, to all the fans watching the stream, thank you for your support.
カバー株式会社の谷郷元昭です。
I'm Tanigo Motoaki of COVER Corp.
実は今回、シオンさんから質問を預かってきています。
Actually, I have some questions from Shion-san.
免許はMTですか？ ATですか？
Is your license MT (Manual) or AT (Automatic)?
免許はマニュアルですね。
My license is manual.
あ、おー！よかったー！
Ah, oh! That's good!
他の免許はもってますか？
Do you have any other licenses?
え、なんかあるのかな？
Eh, I wonder if he has any?
他は免許は持ってないです。
I don't have any other licenses.
あ、車なんだね。
Ah, so just the car.
当時なぜ私に声をかけたのか気になります！理由はありますか？
I'm curious why you reached out to me! Is there a reason?
え、これ気になる！どうしよう、なんもなかったら。
Eh, I'm curious about this! What if there was no reason?
配信者として魅力を感じたからですね。
Because I felt your charm as a streamer.
まあちょっと、やんちゃな感じだったところが、いいなと。
Well, I thought your slightly mischievous side was good.
…っと思いました。
...that's what I thought.
あ、そうなんだ、そうなんだね。逆にね。
Ah, so that's how it was. On the contrary.
あ、これも気になるんだよね。
Ah, I'm curious about this too.
やはりあの、ボカロPとか歌い手さんがしっかり定着していったように、
Just like how Vocaloid producers and singers have become established,
まあ、VTuberも、あの、これから10年とかかけてしっかり職業として定着すればいいなと思っています。
I hope VTubers will also become established as a profession over the next 10 years.
おー。さすが社長っぽいこと…
Oh... as expected of a CEO-like thing to say...
っぽいこと、ぽいというか、社長、社長だ。
or rather, he is the CEO.
そうですね、まあ日本だったり、
Well, in Japan and...
世界征服？世界征服？
World domination? World domination?
あの世界の人たちにとって、まあホロライブっていうものが、
For the people of the world, Hololive...
そのVTuberを、まあ代表するような、あの存在に、まあなっていって、
will become a representative presence of VTubers...
まあ、皆さんに憧れていただけるような、まあそういう存在になっていればいいなと思っております。
and I hope it becomes something everyone admires.
あー、世界征服かと思った、今「世界」って言ったから。
Ah, I thought you meant world domination because you said "world".
シオンさん、改めて、今まで長い間、活動お疲れ様でした。
Shion, once again, thank you for your long activities.
最後の配信、頑張ってくださいね。
Good luck with your final stream.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
見てー、みんなー！
Look, everyone!
Yagoo社長から卒業証書もらいました！
I got a graduation certificate from Yagoo CEO!
見て見て、紫咲シオンって書いてあるんだよ。
Look, it says 'Murasaki Shion'.
裏も！かわいいー。
The back too! It's so cute.
シオン仕様になってる。
It's made Shion-style.
Yagooさん、本当にありがとうございました。
Yagoo, thank you so much.
いっぱい質問答えてもらっちゃって、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for answering many of my questions.
え、見て！
Eh, look!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
超きれいなんだよ。ほら、上にね…
It's so beautiful. Look, up there...
あの惑星とか月とか、いっぱい付いてるの。
planets and moons, there are many of them.
シオン銀色が好きなんだよね。銀色が好きだから、
Shion likes silver. Since I like silver,
銀色と、シオンの、ね、あの色の紫色にしてもらいました。
I had it made with silver and Shion's purple.
超きれいでしょー。
It's so beautiful, right?
で、さっきほどライブをやったステージ…
And the stage where I just did the live...
にも、行けちゃうんですねー。行きましょうか。
I can go there too. Shall we go?
ライブバージョンのステージにチェンジ！
Change to the live version stage!
うおー！すごい！
Whoa! Amazing!
いやめっちゃきれい、本当に。三日月がね、こっちだ。
It's really beautiful. The crescent moon is over here.
きれい。魔界学校なんだよ、これ。
It's beautiful. This is the Demon World Academy.
いや、すごいでしょ。
It's amazing, right?
それでは皆さん、改めて。今日は紫咲シオンの卒業配信に来てくれて、本当にありがとうございます！
So everyone, once again. Thank you so much for coming to Murasaki Shion's graduation stream today!
ハッシュタグはこちら！
Here's the hashtag!
紫咲シオン卒業ライブで、たくさんポストしてください。
Please post a lot with #紫咲シオン卒業ライブ.
スクショ待ってます。
I'm waiting for your screenshots.
トレンド一位、載ってるらしいです。ありがとうございます！
I heard we're trending #1. Thank you so much!
はい、というわけで歌わせていただいた楽曲ですが、一曲目は「三日月」、
Yes, and for the songs I sang, the first one was "Mikazuki",
二曲目は「誰かの心臓になれたら」でした。
and the second was "Dareka no Shinzou ni naretara".
みんな、どうだった？コメントをちょっと、たまに止まったりしてるんだけど、
How was it everyone? I'm looking at the comments, although they sometimes stop,
見れるかな？見てます、見てますけど、
can I see them? I'm watching, but...
ちょっと、タイム、タイムラグなのか、これは。
is this a time, a time lag?
あ、止まっちゃった。止まっちゃって、うん。めっちゃきれいだなって、ステージね。
Ah, it froze. It froze, yeah. The stage is so beautiful.
うん、皆そのステージの、あのまだ次元にいるわ。
Yeah, everyone is still in that stage's dimension.
ありがとうございます、本当に。三日月はね、
Thank you so much. "Mikazuki"
あのー一回歌ったことある曲なんですけど、思い入れがある曲なので、
is a song I've sung once before, and it has special memories for me,
一番最初に歌わせていただきました。
so I sang it first.
「誰かの心臓になれたら」は、あの正直本当バカ高かったです。
As for "Dareka no Shinzou ni naretara", to be honest it was incredibly high-pitched.
高かったけど、高かったけど、頑張って…あ！見えたコメント、見えた！
It was high, but I did my best... Ah! I can see the comments!
ずっと固まってますって言ってる。うん、ずっと固まってたけど動いたよ、今。
They're saying "It's frozen". Yeah, it was frozen but it's moving now!
今ちょうど動きました。うん。
It just started moving now.
コメント、重たいよね、やっぱ。皆いっぱいコメントしてくれてるから、重くなっちゃうんだな。
The comments are heavy, after all. Since everyone is posting so much, it must be heavy.
てか、めっちゃきれいだね、これ。これ。
But this is so beautiful. This, this.
はい、というわけでね。皆たくさんのコメントと、たくさんのツイート、ありがとうございます、本当に。
So yes. Thank you so much for all the comments and tweets.
というわけで、この後はゲストパートになります。
And now, the guest part is coming up.
最後まで見ていってねー！
Please watch until the end!
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it now?
メラメラとたぎれ
Burning and boiling
眠っているだけの正義
Justice that's just sleeping
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero too
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
Thinking I'm unreliable for someone as cool as you
そりゃそうだよな
Well, that's expected
だって今もこうして迷ってる
Because even now I'm hesitating like this
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブとテイクさ
Give and take
かっこいい君には
To the cool you...
僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
I wonder if I'm unreliable.
そりゃそうだよな だって
That's right, because...
今もこうして迷ってる
even now I'm hesitating like this.
手を取ってくれないか
Won't you take my hand?
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
君が僕のヒーローだったように
Just like you were my hero.
今なんじゃない？ メラメラとたぎれ
Isn't it now? Burning and boiling up!
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
There's a sense of justice hiding even in me.
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
look, I'm holding your hand before I knew it.
一体全体そんなに荷物を
Just what in the world, with all that baggage,
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
where are you going carrying it all?
ねえねえ待って 僕にちょっと
Hey, hey, wait, to me, just a bit...
預けてみては
try entrusting it.
信じてばかりの僕と
Me, who only ever believes,
信じることが怖い君と
and you, who is afraid of believing.
どちらが正しいのかなんて
Which of us is right,
誰にも分からないさ
no one can really say.
僕らだけの世界
In a world just for us.
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
補い合えた暁には
In the dawn when we can complement each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
I made you suffer by saying you're cool,
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
and making you all alone...
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
was a little bit my fault, I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきリアルだ
But it's the reality we must face.
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is when I'll save you!
抱えないで 信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't carry it alone, I want you to trust and rely on me.
今なんじゃない？ メラメラとたぎる
Isn't it now? Burning and boiling up,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
there's a sense of justice hiding even in me.
どうしようもない 衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable impulse,
ほら気づけば手を握っている
look, I'm holding your hand before I knew it.
放っておけないそんなに荷物を
I can't leave you alone with all that baggage,
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
where are you going carrying it all?
ほんのちょっと 僕にちょっと
Just a little, to me, just a bit...
預けてみては
try entrusting it.
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
I want to be your hero too.
星座になれたら
If I Could Become a Constellation
もうすぐ時計は6時
Soon the clock will strike six.
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already appearing there.
影を踏んで夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
On the way home, I want to step on shadows and blend into the night.
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search,
ひとつしかない星
there is only one star.
何億光年離れたところから
From hundreds of millions of light-years away,
あんなに輝く
it shines so brightly.
いいな 君は
Must be nice, you're...
みんなから愛されて
...loved by everyone.
いいや 僕は
...No, I've...
ずっとひとりきりさ
...always been all alone.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation,
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
a wish in a moment on a night of falling stars.
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying.
…震えてるシグナル
...A trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could collect them and shape a constellation with you
空見上げて指をさされるような
Like being pointed at as we look up at the sky
繋いだ線 解かないで
Don't let go of the lines connecting us
僕がどんなに 眩しくても
No matter how bright I may be
もうすぐ時計は8時
It's almost 8 o'clock
夜空に満天の星
A sky full of stars
何億光年 離れたところには
In a place billions of light-years away
もうないかもしれない
It might not even exist anymore
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so beautiful it makes me want to cry
いつの日にか 別れが来るから
Because one day, we'll have to say goodbye
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could collect them and shape a constellation with you
彗星みたいに流れる独り言
Soliloquies flowing like comets
消えていく残像は
The fading afterimages
真夜中のプリズム
Are a midnight prism
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could collect them and shape a constellation with you
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If my earnest wish reaches someone
変われるかな 夜の縁を
I wonder if I can change...
なぞるような こんな僕でも
...even someone like me who traces the night's edge
遥か彼方 僕らは出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we ended up meeting
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
It's karma, so we'll meet again and again
雲の隙間で
Between the gaps in the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could collect them and shape a constellation with you
夜広げて描こうよ絵空事
Let's spread the night and draw a pipe dream
暗闇を照らすような
Like something that lights up the darkness
満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon
だから集まって星座になりたい
So I want to gather and become a constellation
色とりどりの光 放つような
Like emitting multicolored light
繋いだ線 解かないよ
I won't let go of the lines connecting us
君がどんなに 眩しくても
No matter how bright you may be
ねぇ 思い出のかけらに
Hey, to the fragments of our memories
名前をつけて保存するなら
If I were to give them a name and save them
「宝物」がぴったりだね
"Treasure" would be just right
そう 心の容量が
Yes, to the point where my heart's capacity
いっぱいになるくらいに
Is about to overflow
過ごしたね
We spent our time together
ときめき色の毎日
In those heart-pounding days
なじんだ制服と上履き
The familiar uniforms and indoor shoes
ホワイトボードの落書き
The scribbles on the whiteboard
明日の入り口に
At tomorrow's entrance
置いてかなくちゃいけないのかな
Do we have to leave them behind?
でもね、会えたよ！
But you know, I met you!
素敵な天使に
A wonderful angel
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation isn't the end
これからも仲間だから
Because we'll be friends from now on, too
一緒の写真たち
The photos we took together
おそろいのキーホルダー
Our matching keychains
いつまでも輝いてる
Will always be shining
ずっと その笑顔 ありがとう
Always, for that smile, thank you
…歌い出したい
...I want to start singing.
見えない ゆっくりなスピードでも
Invisible, even at a slow speed,
きっとあの空は見いてたね
surely that sky was watching us.
何度もつまずいたこと
The many times we stumbled,
それでも最後らまで歩けたこと
and yet we were able to walk to the end.
ふわり 放課後の廊下に
Softly, in the after-school hallway,
こぼれた音符の羽
the wings of notes that spilled out.
ふかふか 積もるまで
Until they pile up deep,
このままでいれたらいいのにな
I wish we could stay just like this.
でもね、触れたよ！
But hey, we touched it!
愛すべき天使に
A lovable angel.
ただいま、って言いたくなる
It makes me want to say 'I'm home',
この場所は変わらないよ
this place will never change.
メールの受信箱
The email inbox,
マルしたカレンダー
the circled calendar.
とびっきりの夢と出会い くれた
To the music that gave me
音楽にありがとう
extraordinary dreams and encounters, thank you.
駅のホーム 変わらぬ道
The station platform, the unchanging road.
離れてても同じ空見上げて
Even if we're apart, looking up at the same sky,
ユニゾンで歌おう
let's sing in unison.
でもね、会えたよ！
But hey, we met her!
素敵な天使に
A wonderful angel.
卒業は終わりじゃない
Graduation isn't the end,
これからも仲間だから
because we'll be comrades from now on.
大好きって言うなら
If you say 'I love you',
大大好きって返すよ
I'll return it with 'I reaaaally love you'.
忘れ物もないよね
There's nothing left behind, right?
ずっと永遠に一緒だよ
We'll be together forever.
カラフル
作詞・作曲：渡辺 翔
Colorful
Lyrics & Composition: Sho Watanabe
いつもモノクロだった瞳の奥の
In the depths of my eyes that were always monochrome,
景色捨てたら夢見つけた
when I threw away the scenery, I found a dream.
何もない世界でつくる絆は
The bonds created in a world with nothing
強い意志与えた
gave me a strong will.
裏返した
Turned inside out,
日常もまた
everyday life once again.
走っていく先に
In the place where I'm running to,
君はいた
you were there.
触れた心は輝いた
The heart I touched shone,
鮮やかな色になって
becoming a vibrant color,
羽ばたくよ 希望乗せて
and spread its wings, carrying hope.
無限に広がる空の下集まった
Gathered under the infinitely spreading sky,
願い守り進めば
if we move forward protecting our wishes,
まだ誰も知らない明日へと
towards a tomorrow that no one knows yet.
引き寄せられるように覗いた瞬間
The moment I peeked as if being drawn in,
光の糸は君包んだ
the thread of light enveloped you.
細く千切れそうな絡まった運命
The thin, seemingly tearing, entangled fate.
きっとまだ 変われる
Surely we can still change.
間違えても信じた道は新しい景色を
Even if I make a mistake, the path I believed in [will show] a new scenery.
新しい景色を
A new scenery...
照らす
illuminating...
だろう
it will be.
巡る
Turning around...
時の中笑って
laughing within the time,
様々な想い持って
holding various feelings,
始めよう またイチから
let's begin again from scratch.
辿り着いた儚い奇跡 壊れないように
The fleeting miracle we reached, so it won't break...
手を伸ばし 繋げば
I reach out my hand, and if we connect,
ほら
Look,
君は側で いつまでも...
you are by my side forever...
まだ透明な 私たちは
We, who are still transparent,
どんな色にでも 染まることが
can be dyed any color at all,
出来るから 夢叶えよう
so let's make our dreams come true.
走って行く先に
Where I run toward,
君はいた
you were there.
触れた
Touched,
心は輝いた
my heart shone brightly.
鮮やかな色になって
Becoming a vivid color,
羽ばたくよ 希望乗せて
I'll fly away, carrying our hopes.
無限に広がる空の下集まった
Under the infinitely spreading sky, we gathered...
願い 守り 行けば
wishes... protecting them, if we go...
君と誓ったあの日の記憶
the memory of that day I swore with you,
今 超えて 過去から
now beyond, from the past,
まだ誰も知らない
to a tomorrow that no one knows yet,
明日へと
to the future.
はい、というわけでぺこらちゃんに来てもらいました！
Yes, so Pekora-chan has come to join us!
来ましたー！ぺこらちゃん！
I've come! Pekora-chan!
卒業するかーい！
Are you graduating?!
ぺこらちゃん、来てくれてありがとう。卒業ライブに。
Pekora-chan, thank you for coming to my graduation live.
いやいやシオンちゃん、むしろ呼んでくれてありがとうぺこだけど。
No no, Shion-chan, actually thank you for inviting me-peko.
ありがとう。一緒に「カラフル」歌えてめっちゃ嬉しかった。
Thank you. I was so happy we could sing 'Colorful' together.
ねえ「カラフル」ね。
Right, 'Colorful'.
そう、まどマギの曲じゃん。二人で歌う曲だなと思って。
Yeah, it's a Madoka Magica song. I thought it's a song for two.
ぺこらちゃんの声に絶対合うと思ったわけよ。
I thought it would definitely suit Pekora-chan's voice.
ほうほうほう、エモいし。
Ho ho ho, and it's emotional.
そう。だから一緒に歌いたいなと思って。
Exactly. So I really wanted to sing it together.
じゃあ二人は魔法少女ってこと？
So the two of us are magical girls?
そういうこと！
That's right!
我ら、天下統一打ち放った二人！
We are the two who unleashed national unification!
わせつれっしょ。
Waseteru-sho.
わせつれっしょあれ魔法少女じゃねえし！
Waseteru-sho isn't a magical girl thing!
やめてよ、魔法少女の話してたのに急にさ。
Stop it, we were talking about magical girls and then suddenly...
今急に言ったら覚えてるのかなっていうので。
I thought if I said it suddenly, I'd see if you remembered.
そういうことね。
I see.
ちゃんといいなよ、天下統一の下り。
Make sure to say it properly, that national unification routine.
でもそうだったんだ、そういう選曲だったんだね。
But I see, so that's why you chose this song.
ぺこら嬉しかったもん、カラフル好きだったから。
Pekora was happy, because I liked Colorful.
まどマギの曲でカラフル歌いたいなっていう。
I wanted to sing Colorful from Madoka Magica.
もうなんか途中でぺこらちゃんがまどかに見えてきたもん。
At some point, I started seeing Pekora-chan as Madoka.
まじで言ってる？え、待って、まどかかも？
Are you serious? Wait, maybe I am Madoka?
え、かわいい。まどかかもって思ってきて。
Eh, cute. Thinking 'maybe she is Madoka'.
ってことは暁美ほむら？
Does that mean you're Akemi Homura?
はい、なんか見えてきたかも。救いたい。
Yes, I might be starting to see it. I want to save you.
ぺこらを救いたい。
I want to save Pekora.
ぺこらを救う世界線にしたい。
I want to make this a world line where I save Pekora.
シオンは何度も死んでぺこらを救うんだ。
Shion will die many times to save Pekora.
まじかよ、なんかむしろ逆じゃないの？
Seriously? Isn't it actually the opposite?
シオンを救うぺこらの方がいいんじゃないの？
Isn't it better to have Pekora saving Shion?
なんでぺこらを救うシオンになってるの？
Why is it Shion saving Pekora?
それおもろすぎるな、まじで。
That's too funny, seriously.
え、なんかさ、今まで天下統一活動とかたくさんしてきた。
Well, we've done a lot of 'national unification' activities together.
ねえ、その天下統一さ、いつやったと思ってるの？
Hey, when do you think we did that national unification?
天下統一、結構最近。
National unification was quite recently.
最近じゃねえよ！ぺこらたちって初コラボとかもう5、6年前とかじゃん。
It wasn't recently! Our first collab was like 5 or 6 years ago.
さっきちょっと話してたけどさ。
We were just talking about it earlier.
マリオカート、ありましたね。
Mario Kart, that happened.
あの時のぺこちゃんは
Peko-chan back then...
なんてういういしくて可愛かったんでしょう
was so innocent and cute.
今は？
And now?
今も可愛いぺこね
Still cute now, peko.
きのこ、きのこ取れなかったぺこ
Mushrooms, I couldn't get the mushrooms, peko.
うわあああ、やめてぺこ
Waaah, stop it, peko!
やめてぺこ
Stop it, peko!
あ、落ちたぺこーみたいな
Ah, I fell, peko—like that.
そう思ったらさ、シオンちゃんってマジ変わんないかも
Thinking back, Shion-chan really hasn't changed.
え、ガチで？
Wait, seriously?
最初から今まで？
From the beginning until now?
え、なんか...
Well, somehow...
最初からクソガキだし
You've been a brat since the start.
でも何回か...
But after a few times...
やっぱ遊ぶたびにクソガキ感もありつつ
whenever we hung out, you still felt like a brat,
大人の部分もちゃんとあるんだなっていうのは
but I saw you have a mature side too.
え、ずっと言ってくれてるよね？
Eh, you've always said that, right?
ぺこーら、ずっと想ってた
Pekora's always felt that way.
そう、でもぺこちゃんはあの時は
Yeah, but Peko-chan back then...
ぺこ！
Peko!
あ、落ちたぺこ！
Ah, I fell, peko!
わあ、シオン先輩！
Whoa, Shion-senpai!
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
あの時は、ほら、よそ行き人見知りパターンぺこらだったし
Back then, I was in my formal, shy mode.
シオンちゃんって呼んでって一生言い続けたら
If I kept telling you to call me Shion-chan forever,
シオンちゃんって呼んでくれるようになった
then you'd start calling me Shion-chan.
確かにぺこらは結構先輩とかにはさ
It's true, Pekora usually calls seniors...
先輩って言うタイプぺこだから
by adding "senpai," so...
でも今は言い慣れた、シオンちゃんとかって
But now I'm used to it—saying Shion-chan.
すごい言い慣れたぺこだけど
I've gotten very used to it, peko.
やっぱ最初のその先輩からシオンちゃんって
Changing from "senpai" to "Shion-chan"...
呼び方を変える時は、めちゃめちゃ大変だった
for the first time was really hard.
あ、頑張ってるんだろうなっていうのが...
Ah, I could tell you were trying hard...
めちゃ頑張ってるんだろうなっていうのが伝わってきて
It really came through that you were putting in effort.
なんか、ちょっと申し訳ないなって思ってたんだけど
I actually felt a little bad about it, but...
あ、そうなんだ？
Oh, really?
なんか、乗り越えてくれた
You overcame it for me.
頑張りを乗り越えて、シオンちゃん定着したから
Through that effort, Shion-chan stuck.
そう、もうこれからもシオンちゃんって呼んでいくからね、ぺこーらは
Yeah, Pekora will keep calling you Shion-chan from now on too.
そう、最近でも天下統一活動してきて
Yeah, we've been doing our Tenka Toitsu activities recently.
今やって、今も天下統一中なんだけど
We're doing it now, we're still in the middle of it.
そうだよ、今まさに天下統一活動中だからね
That's right, we're right in the middle of it.
天下統一は解散しないからね
Tenka Toitsu is not disbanding.
そうだよ、シオンちゃんが卒業したとしても天下統一は永久活動中だから
Even if Shion-chan graduates, Tenka Toitsu will be active forever.
天下は統一していくから、これからもね
We'll keep on unifying the realm together.
これからもね、最近も色々天下統一してきたよね
We have recently, haven't we?
何だっけ？
What did we do?
何だっけ？じゃねえよ！
Don't say "What did we do!"
何だっけ？じゃねえよ！もうねえのかよ！
Don't say "What did we do!" Is there nothing left?!
一つくらい、マリオカートね！
At least one thing... Mario Kart!
あ、そうだね、マリオカートね
Ah, right, Mario Kart.
あとは？
What else?
あとは、カラフル歌ったね！
And we sang "Colorful"!
今や、今さっきや！
That was just now! A moment ago!
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
ライブとかでもいっぱい歌ったし
We've sung a lot at concerts too.
そう、ぺこらたち結構さ
Yeah, we've really...
活動してきたよ
done so much together.
5年前だよ、初コラボ
Our first collab was five years ago.
5年前？え、何年デビューして？
Five years? How long since our debut?
今6年目、7年目なんだよ
We're in our 6th, going on 7th year.
うわあ...
Wow...
長い...
That's long...
マジで言ってる？そうなんだよ
Are you serious? It really has been.
長いよね
It's been a long time.
ぺこーら今日シオンちゃんに伝えたいことがある
Pekora has something to tell Shion-chan today.
何？
What is it?
ちょっと待ってて
Wait a moment.
え、何？
Wait, what?
ぺこーら、待って
Pekora, wait.
（泣き声）
(Crying sounds)
嘘でしょ...
No way...
シオンちゃんが今日卒業してしまうということで
Since Shion-chan is graduating today,
手紙を書いてきたぺこ
I wrote a letter, peko.
びっくりしたでしょ？
Surprised?
びっくりした、ガチで知らなかった
I'm shocked, I really didn't know.
見ないで...
Don't look...
ガチで知らなかった、嘘...
I seriously had no idea...
じゃあちょっと読ませてもらいます
Well then, let me read it.
シオンちゃんへ
To Shion-chan.
ヤッホー、もう卒業か...
Yahoo, graduating already, huh?
寂しいよ
I'm lonely.
なんでやめちゃうんだよ！
Why are you quitting?!
って言っても困らせるだけだと思うので
But saying that would only trouble you,
ぺこーらがシオンちゃんに思ってることを伝えます
so I'll just tell you what's on my mind.
シオンちゃんと初めてコミュニケーションを取ったのは
The first time we communicated...
ぺこーらがホロライブに入った時に
was when I joined Hololive...
シオンちゃんからDiscordで声をかけてくれたのが
and you reached out to me on Discord.
最初だったよね
That was the beginning.
懐かしいね
That brings back memories.
ぺこらは人見知りすごかったから
I was incredibly shy back then,
先輩から声をかけてもらえることがとても嬉しかったぺこ
so having a senior reach out made me so happy.
よかった...
I'm glad...
そこから色々なコラボをして
Since then, through many collabs...
子供っぽいところもありつつ、大人の部分もあるし
I saw both your childish and mature sides.
先輩なのに話しやすいし、遊んでて楽しいし
Even as a senior, you're so easy to talk to.
そして何より優しいシオンちゃんが大好きです
And above all, I love you for your kindness.
ありがとう...
Thank you...
恥ずかしいな...
This is embarrassing...
USJ旅行も、シオンちゃんとだから行けたんだと思う
Our USJ trip was only possible because of you.
知らなかったクレーンゲームの巧さや...
Discovering how good you are at crane games...
気配り屋さんなところ...
and how thoughtful you are...
ここでは話せないこともたくさん話せた旅行だった
we shared so many things I can't even mention here.
たくさん話したね
We really did talk a lot.
今度はどこへ行こうか？
Where should we go next?
正直、卒業すると聞いた時は...
To be honest, when I heard you were graduating...
驚きつつも、どこか腑に落ちる自分もいて
I was surprised, but part of me also understood.
残り少ない時間でたくさん思い出を作りたいと思った
I wanted to make many memories in the time left.
作れたかな？
Did we make them?
作れたよ！いっぱい天下統一したもんね
We did! We unified the realm so many times.
（笑い声）
(Laughing)
卒業はとても寂しいし、悲しいけど
Graduation is very lonely and sad, but...
ぺこらとシオンちゃんの関係は...
The relationship between you and me...
ペカ統一は永久不滅！
Peka-Unification is eternal and immortal!
はい！
Yes!
それじゃ、本当に最後の挨拶をしますよ！
Then, I'll do the truly final greeting!
はい！
Yes!
我ら！ペカ統一！
We are! Peka-Unification!
せーの！
Ready, go!
兎田ぺこら！シオンちゃん大好き！ありがとうぺこら！
Usada Pekora! I love you Shion-chan! Thank you Pekora!
じゃ、まだ多分このあとも卒業ライブがあると思うから、頑張ってね。
Well, since I think your graduation live still continues, do your best.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これあとで渡すから。
I'll give you this later.
え？読みますあとで。ありがとうシオンちゃん。
Eh? I'll read it later. Thank you Shion-chan.
じゃ、シオンちゃんまたね！ありがとう！
Well, see you later Shion-chan! Thanks!
マジかよ...
Are you serious...?
気分次第です僕の 敵を選んで戦う少年
Depending on my mood, I am a boy who picks out his enemies to fight
叶えたい未来もなくて 夢に描かれるのを待ってた
With no future I want to fulfill, I was just waiting to be drawn into a dream
そのくせ未来が怖くて 明日を嫌って過去に願って
But still, the future is scary, I hate tomorrow, and wish upon the past
もうどうしようもなくなって叫ぶんだ
There's nothing more I can do, I scream
明日よ明日よもう来ないでよって
"Tomorrow, tomorrow, don't come yet"
そんな僕を置いて
Leaving that kind of me behind
月は沈み陽は昇る
The moon sets and the sun rises
けれどその夜は違ったんだ
But that night was different
君は僕の手を
When you took my hand
空へ舞え世界の彼方 闇を照らす回旋
Dance to the sky, beyond the world, the rotation that lights the darkness
君と僕をさあ また繋いでゆこう
Let's connect you and me again
夢で終わってしまうのなら 昨日を返してなんて
If it's just going to end as a dream, don't say
言わないでなんでなんて言わないから
"Give me back yesterday," because I won't say "why"
また明日も君とこうやって 笑わせて
Make me laugh like this with you tomorrow too
あれから世界は変わったって 本気で思ったって
Even if I seriously thought the world had changed since then
期待した世界はどうしたって 未来は残酷で
No matter what, the world I expected and the future are cruel
それでもいったって きっと見ていた世界は本当に綺麗だったんだ
Even so, the world I was surely looking at was truly beautiful
忘れてないさ 思いだせるようにしまってるの
I haven't forgotten, I've tucked it away so I can remember
君がいてもいなくても 飛べるなんて
Whether you're there or not, saying I can fly...
もう一人じゃ歩くことさえ僕は
I can't even walk alone anymore
支配も愛も風に吐いた幻想
Domination and love are illusions spat into the wind
壊してくれって願ってもがいたって
Even if I prayed "destroy them" and struggled
願ったんなら叶えてしまえって
If I wished for it, then make it come true
君はいて
You are here
またさああの夜に 会いにゆこうともがいてた
I wonder if you, who were struggling
君はいないかな それでも今まで僕のことだから
to go meet that night again, are gone? Even so, it's just like me
お別れ嫌いよ 笑ってよ
I hate goodbyes, so please laugh
未来ももっと君といたいから
Because I want to be with you more in the future
叫ぼう今日の日をいつか思い出す 未来の僕ら
Let's shout, our future selves will remember today one day
はい、ということでね。いやー、次のゲストなんですが、
Alright, so... well, as for the next guest,
ちょっとハードルが高そうなんだよね。
the hurdle seems a bit high.
めちゃくちゃ名高い魔導書には、
In a very famous magic book,
召喚される人が喜ぶものを捧げると成功するって書いてあったんだけど...
it said that if you offer something that the person being summoned likes, it will succeed...
やるしかない。磨いとこ。よいしょ。
I just have to do it. Better polish it. Heave-ho.
磨いて磨いて...よし。
Polish, polish... alright.
はい！
There!
さあ、出てこい！
Now, come out!
わぁ〜！
Waa~!
えー、シオン先輩！
Eh, Shion-senpai!
本当に出きた！
You really did it!
待って！待って！
Wait! Wait!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
本当に迎えてくれて...
For really welcoming me...
キモい！キモい！
Gross! Gross!
なんか思ってたのと違うかも！
This might be different from what I thought!
もうすぐお尻に届きそう！
I'm almost reaching the butt!
キモ！キモすぎる！
Gross! Too gross!
逃げないで！逃げないで！
Don't run away! Don't run away!
え？
Eh?
本当に？
Really?
ちょっとよく見せて、ちょっと
Let me see a bit, just a bit
ほうほう、どうぞ
Ho-ho, go ahead
ちょっと立って、立って
Stand up for a bit, stand up
え？
Eh?
まあ、後で全部見せてあげるのに...
Well, I'll show you everything later...
何ですか何ですか？どこが見たいんですか？
What is it, what is it? Where do you want to see?
あ、でも沙花叉...
Ah, but Sakamata...
か、これは本当に沙花叉...
Th-this really is Sakamata...
見た目は沙花叉っぽいよね
Appearance-wise, it's like Sakamata
もちろん！
Of course!
なんかちょっと、キモすぎるか？
Is it maybe a bit too gross?
いやいやいや！失敗した可能性があるな、これ
No no no! There's a possibility I failed, with this
心外ですか？
How heartless!
沙花叉を...
Sakamata...
え？
Eh?
沙花叉はこんなもんですよ！
Sakamata is like this!
なんだ...
What...
何を夢を抱いてるんですか！
What kind of dream are you harboring!
キモかったか、キモかったか？
Was it gross, was it gross?
そうだよ、そうだよ！
That's right, that's right!
そうですよ！最初からキモかったか！
That's right! Was I gross from the start!
あ、沙花叉だ、沙花叉だ
Ah, it's Sakamata, it's Sakamata
お久しぶりです！
It's been a while!
元気してた？
How have you been?
会いたかったから呼んでくれたんですよね？
You called me because you wanted to see me, right?
あー、そう、まあまあまあ...
Ah, yeah, well, well...
すごく会いたかったみたいですね！
Looks like you really wanted to see me!
そうだよ、そう！会いたかったよ！
That's right, yeah! I wanted to see you!
元気もらえました！
I got some energy!
あの歯ブラシこれから使いますので！
I'll use that toothbrush from now on!
あ、沙花叉、なんで歯ブラシで召喚されたの？
Ah, Sakamata, why were you summoned with a toothbrush?
え？
Eh?
いや、多分なんですけど...
Well, I think...
シオン先輩の匂いがしたと思ったらここにいたので
I thought I smelled Shion-senpai, and then I was here
やっぱり本能かな、と。はい。
I guess it's instinct. Yes.
あ、匂いしたんだ、歯ブラシから
Ah, you smelled it from the toothbrush
しましたしました！最高ですよ！
I did, I did! It's the best!
最高ですよ！
It's the best!
あ、口開けていただいたら鼻突っ込めますから、全然！
Ah, if you open your mouth, I can stick my nose in, totally!
最悪だ...
The worst...
キモいな、今日もキモさマシマシですね！
Gross, today the grossness is extra large!
あ、沙花叉の卒業ライブの時もね...
Ah, during Sakamata's graduation live too...
結構キモいお願い、いっぱいいっぱいされたんだけど...
I was asked for quite a lot of gross favors...
最高でしたね、あれはあれで。うん。
That was the best, in its own way. Yeah.
変わらない、変わらない感じがして、うん。良かった、本当に。
It feels like nothing's changed, yeah. It was good, really.
良かった、変わらない感じね
Good, the feeling of not changing
ね、あ、ははは！
Yeah, ah, hahaha!
あ！
Ah!
そういう連打...
That kind of rapid fire...
シンプルに引いちゃった
I simply got turned off
何で引いてるんですか！でも沙花叉も元気そうで良かったよ、シオン本当に。
Why are you turned off! But I'm glad Sakamata seems well too, really, Shion.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
会えて良かった！
Glad we could meet!
ということで、ありがとうございましたー
So, with that, thank you very much—
ちょっと待て！
Wait a minute!
せっかく来てくれたんだから！
Since you went through the trouble of coming!
え、もうこれでいいってこと？
Eh, you mean this is enough?
え、いや、嬉しいですよ！
Eh, no, I'm happy!
また呼んでください！
Please call me again!
ちょっとちょっと！雑談とかで！
Wait, wait! For a chat or something!
またって何？またって。シオン卒業するんだけど。
What do you mean 'again'? Again. I'm graduating, you know.
あ、そうか！待って待って！あ、待って、あ、待ってないんだけど
Ah, that's right! Wait, wait! Ah, wait, ah, I'm not waiting though
いやね、せっかく来てくれたんだから...
Well, since you've come all this way...
一緒に歌おうよ！
Let's sing together!
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
もうちょっとなんかこう、本当に、あの、切羽詰まる感じで...
A bit more like, really, that, feeling cornered...
「一緒に、一緒がいい」って！
'Together, I want to be together!'
「一緒じゃなきゃ嫌だ」って！言ってもらえます？
'I hate it if we're not together!' Could you say that?
な、何でだろうな、うん。
Wh, I wonder why, yeah.
沙花叉の卒業ライブの時、シオン結構あの、頑張ったと思うんだけど
During Sakamata's graduation live, I think I worked quite hard
えー、シオン先輩楽しかったです！ありがとうございました！
Eh, Shion-senpai, it was fun! Thank you very much!
待て待て待て！沙花叉、沙花叉！
Wait, wait, wait! Sakamata, Sakamata!
一緒がいい！
Together is good!
よし、きた！
Alright, there it is!
行きますか！
Shall we go!
そして！歌お！やった！歌ってくれるって！
And! Let's sing! Yay! She says she'll sing!
歌いますか！
Shall we sing!
ということでね、はい。
So, with that, yes.
それでは聴いてください！
Now, please listen!
スパークル！
Sparkle!
まだこの世界は 僕を飼い慣らしてたいみたいだ
It seems this world still wants to tame me
望み通りいいだろう 美しくもがくよ
Fine, just as you wish, I'll struggle beautifully
互いの砂時計 眺めながらキスをしようよ
Let's kiss while watching each other's hourglasses
「さよなら」から一番遠い 場所で待ち合わせよう
Let's meet at the place farthest from "goodbye"
ついに時は来た
Finally, the time has come
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday, it was the prologue of the prologue
飛ばし読みでいいから
Skimming is fine,
こっからが僕だよ
from here on, it's me.
経験と知識と
With experience and knowledge,
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
and a bit of moldy courage...
いまだかつてないスピードで
at a speed never seen before,
君のもとへダイブを
I'll dive to where you are.
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
In a drowse, with a lukewarm cola,
ここでないどこかを夢見たよ
I dreamed of somewhere else.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window,
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
on a morning being swayed by the train.
運命だとか未来だとかって言葉が
Words like "fate" or "future"...
どれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
no matter how far they stretch their hands,
場所で僕ら恋をする
at a place they can't reach, we fall in love.
At a place they can't reach, we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
Even the hands of the clock,
横目に見ながら進む
move while looking at us sideways.
こんな世界を二人で一生
Through this world for a lifetime, the two of us,
いや、何章でも
no, for however many chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's survive.
「はじめまして」なんてさ
Saying things like "Nice to meet you"...
遥か彼方へと追いやって
driving them far, far away.
1000年周期を一日で息しよう
Let's breathe through a 1000-year cycle in a day.
辞書にある言葉で
With words in the dictionary,
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world they made up.
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope,
8月の月曜
on a Monday in August...
君は僕の前で
In front of me,
ハニかんでは澄ましてみせた
you acted shy and then cool.
この世界の教科書のような
With a smile like a textbook
笑顔で
for this world.
嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の未来を
Days like a lie, an irregular future,
悲劇だっていいから望んだよ
I wished for them, even if it's a tragedy.
そしたらドアの外に
Then, outside the door,
君が全部抱えて立ってたよ
you were standing there carrying everything.
運命だとか未来だとかって言葉が
Words like "fate" or "future"...
どれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
no matter how far they stretch their hands,
場所で
at a place they can't reach...
僕ら
Shall we...
遊ぼうか
play?
愛し方さえも
Even the way of loving
君の匂いがした
smelled like you.
歩き方さえも
Even the way of walking
その笑い声がした
sounded like your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる
All of you that
君のすべてを
will someday disappear...
この目に焼き付けておくことは
searing it into these eyes
もう権利なんかじゃない
is no longer a right;
義務だと思うんだ
I think it's a duty.
運命だとか未来だとかって言葉が
Words like "fate" or "future"...
どれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
no matter how far they stretch their hands,
場所で僕ら恋をする
at a place they can't reach, we fall in love.
At a place they can't reach, we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
Even the hands of the clock,
横目に見ながら進む
move while looking at us sideways.
こんな世界を二人で一生
Through this world for a lifetime, the two of us,
いや、何章でも
no, for however many chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's survive.
時ノ雨、最終戦争 / 作詞・作曲: Orangestar
Toki no Ame, Saishuu Sensou / Lyrics & Composition: Orangestar
答えて ねぇ
Answer me, please.
にわか雨が寄せる街の夜へ
To the night in the city where the shower gathers.
沈む世界 感覚遡行
A sinking world, sensory regression.
「きっと僕ら生まれながら
"Surely we were born...
何処にもないコタエを探してる」
searching for an answer that doesn't exist."
応えて ねぇ
Answer me, please.
叶えて 何を？
Grant it. What?
『今日の世界はいかがです？』
"How is the world today?"
きっと言われずとも
Surely, even if you're not told,
君は君を知っているだろうともさ
you know yourself.
けどまだ信じられぬだろう
But I still cannot believe it.
終わる日々の果てで
At the end of the day, when it ends.
泣き出したその彼方
If I cry, the answer is...
終わらない戦と悪が咲いて
Unending wars and evil bloom.
なんてただ期待も無い
I have no expectations.
なんて君は君をかき消した
You erased yourself.
時の流れに希望さえ
In the passage of time, even hope...
描けない世界で
...cannot be drawn in this world.
正しさなんて誰にも無いから
Since there's no "right" answer for anyone,
君は何を願ってもいいの
you can wish for anything.
いいの
It's okay.
コタエは無いよ
There is no answer.
僕のことなどきっと僕はまた
Surely I will again...
悲しみの身代わりにする
...make myself a scapegoat for sadness.
孤独の中遠く浮かぶ昨日が
Yesterday floats distantly in the loneliness.
今日で世界は終わります
The world ends today.
君が拒めどその群れに
Even if you refuse, in that crowd...
咲かせ死に花
...make the flower of death bloom.
成るは厭なり想いは成らず
To become is to loathe, feelings don't materialize.
君の全てはね
Everything about you, you see...
止まない憂いの最中
In the midst of unending sorrow,
二つ感情は対を成して
two emotions form a pair.
願いを放つ君は
Releasing your wish, you...
覚えてるかな あの日涙の意味を
...remember the meaning of the tears that day?
この夜はまだ終わらない
This night isn't over yet.
明けの夜が今日咲いてたって
Even if the dawning night bloomed today,
僕はさ嫌いじゃないって
I don't hate it.
さくらい空が跳ねる
The cherry blossom sky leaps.
泣きやんだ今日にさらば
Farewell to today when the crying stopped.
変わらない想いを振り翳すように
Wielding unchanging feelings...
生きていく
...I will live on.
泣きながらでいいさ それを繰り返して
It's okay to cry, repeat it until...
笑える生涯
...a life where you can laugh.
また明日の雨に打たれたって
Even if hit by tomorrow's rain again,
いつかこの世に生まれてきてよかったって
so one day I can say I'm glad I was born...
言えるようになるかな その日まで
will I be able to? Until that day...
負けないよ
I won't give up.
ただ声一つ / 作詞・作曲: MIMI
Tada Koe Hitotsu / Lyrics & Composition: MIMI
続く 時間の欠片を
I'm only collecting fragments of time...
集めている
...that go by endlessly.
ただ過ぎる ノートの余白に書く
I write in the margins of my notebook,
「答えは、いつ？」
"When is the answer?"
"When will the answer be written?"
ほんのり小さな感情へ
To the faint little emotion
愛をひとつ
Just one love
またね またね
See you again, see you again
夜に咲く温度と灯るまで
Until the temperature blooming in the night illuminates
呼吸ひとつ
Just one breath
生きる 生きる
I live, I live
優しい日々の横で泣かぬように
Beside the gentle days, so as not to cry
あぁ 泣かぬように
Ah, so as not to cry
ちっちゃな言葉 チクチクしたの
Tiny words made me prickle
キリが無いけどさ
Though there is no end to them...
それを忘れたふり 疲れたよ
I pretended to forget, I was tired
夜よ抱きしめて
Night, hold me tight
今日だって笑う 笑う
Even if I laugh, laugh today
泣いちゃう僕を隠すために笑う
To hide the me who wants to cry
言えないことは 言わないで良い
It's fine not to say things I can't say
と思えたら軽くなれるのかな
If I could think that, I might become lighter
愛をひとつ
Just one love
またね またね
See you again, see you again
夜に咲く温度と灯るまで
Until the temperature blooming in the night illuminates
呼吸ひとつ
Just one breath
生きる 生きる
I live, I live
優しい日々の横で泣かぬように
Beside the gentle days, so as not to cry
愛をひとつ
Just one love
またね またね
See you again, see you again
あぁ
Ah...
愛をひとつ
Just one love
またね またね
See you again, see you again
優しい日々の横で笑うように
Beside the gentle days, so as to laugh
吐き出す気持ちは簡単だけど
I let out my simple emotions
でも生きるの難易度高すぎて
But living is too challenging
どうにも解けない問いだらけ
Too many unsolvable problems
さっぱり 記っ記り 前向いて
No need to forget and face forward
なんてしなくて良いから抱きしめて
All you need to do is hold me
愛をひとつ
Just one love
またね またね
See you again, see you again
はい、というわけでゲストパートとソロパートでした！
All right, so that was the guest part and solo part!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
ゲストパートはね、メア、おかゆと、ころねと歌いましたね。
For the guest part, I sang with Mea, Okayu, and Korone.
まず1曲目、から始まって、
Starting with the first song,
星間ならびたら白上フブキ、フブキちゃんとすいちゃんが来てくれました！
and then "Seikan Narabitara", Fubuki-chan and Sui-chan joined me!
天使にふれたよで船長と歌って、
I sang "Tenshi ni Fureta yo" with Senchou,
カラフルをぺこちゃんと歌いました！
and "Colorful" with Peko-chan!
いや、そう、ぺこちゃんとの...
Yeah, that's right, the one with Peko-chan...
MCをやったんだけど、
We did the MC segment together,
まさか手紙を読んでくれると思わなくて。
but I never thought she'd read a letter to me.
いや、正直本当に、あの、ビックリが勝っちゃって。
Honestly, I was mostly just really surprised.
あの、「え？手紙書いてきてくれたの？」ってなって。
I was like, "Huh? You wrote a letter for me?"
ちょっと「え、え、本当にえ？」みたいな感じのまま...
I was just like, "Wait, what, really?"
驚きを隠せなかったんだけど。
I couldn't hide my surprise.
いや、本当に嬉しい。今ちょっとウルっとね、あの、聞いてて、思いました。
I'm really happy. Listening back to it now makes me feel a bit emotional.
そう、ぺこちゃんとカラフル歌って、MCにも出てもらいました。
Yeah, I sang "Colorful" with Peko-chan, and she joined for the MC.
で、明日の夜空哨戒班、2期生で歌いました！
And then the 2nd generation sang "Asu no Yozora Shoukaihan"!
集まってくれてありがとな。
Thanks for gathering together.
スパークルを、
Sparkle...
沙花叉クロヱ、沙花叉と一緒にね、スパークルを歌いました！
I sang "Sparkle" together with Sakamata Chloe!
魔法が成功するかちょっとわかんなかったんですけど、
I wasn't sure if the magic would work,
魔法が成功したみたいで、召喚されてきてくれました。歯ブラシで。
but it seems it was a success, and she was summoned. With a toothbrush.
「またいつでも呼んでくださいね」とか言ってたけど、
She said, "Please call me again anytime,"
卒業ライブなんだわ、こっちは。
but this is my graduation LIVE.
卒業するんだわ。
I'm graduating.
沙花叉ありがとうね、来てくれて。
Sakamata, thank you for coming.
「ときめき最終戦争」と「ただ声一つ」、2曲連続で、
I sang "Tokimeki Saisyuu Sensou" and "Tada Koe Hitotsu" back-to-back,
歌わせていただきました。どうだったでしょうか？
I sang them. How was it?
手紙ね。手紙本当にビックリしたね。
The letter. I was really surprised by the letter.
沙花叉もね、本当に。みんなビックリしてた、ビックリした？
And Sakamata too. Everyone was surprised, were you guys surprised?
ありがとね、とか。今ちょっとコメント見てんだよ。
Thank you. I'm looking at the comments now.
コメント早すぎてさ、見れねーよ。
The comments are too fast, I can't keep up.
早すぎるよ、コメント。
Too fast, the comments.
「行かないで」... 卒業します。
"Don't go"... I'm graduating.
というわけでね、あと2曲となりました。
So, there are only two songs left.
次に歌う曲なんですが、
The next song I'm going to sing,
実はこの配信をするにあたり、
actually, when preparing for this stream,
何を最後にみんなに伝えられたらいいかなっていうのを、
I was thinking about what I wanted to tell everyone at the end.
考えてたんですよ。
I was thinking about it.
その中で、実はホロライブの公式ページにある、
And then, actually, on Hololive's official page,
シオンのプロフィール...
Shion's profile...
公式ページのプロフって何だよって
You might wonder what's on my official profile...
人がいっぱいそうだけど
many people probably do.
実はあのプロフィール書いてある人 結構書いてあるから
But actually, people who write their profiles...
なんか好きな食べ物とか 誕生日 身長とかの下に
often list things like favorite foods, birthdays,
「夢」っていう欄が実はあるんですよ
height, and then there's a 'Dream' section.
ある人とない人がいるかもしれないんだけど
Some people might have it, and some might not.
実はその夢のところに シオンが書いた言葉があるんだけど
In that 'Dream' section, I wrote something:
「世界のみんなを笑顔にする」なんですよね
"To make everyone in the world smile."
まあでも 世界のみんなとまではちょっと難しいかもしれないけど
Well, making everyone in the world smile might be hard...
せめてシオンのことを好きでいてくれる人には
but at the very least, for those who love me,
絶対笑顔でいてほしいと思ったから
I definitely want you to keep smiling.
そんな気持ちで次の曲を歌いたいと思ってます
With that feeling, I want to sing the next song.
それでは聞いてください メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット
Please listen: Mage of Violet.
暗い方ばっか見てないで
Don't just look at the dark side.
ウラッパッパッパ パラリラ踊れよ
Urappappappa, dance parari!
正解が今日を誘導せ
Let the right answer guide today.
華やかなワガママ称えよ
Celebrate this brilliant selfishness.
いないいないばあでこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo! Look over here.
したたかな未来を咲かせよ
Let a sturdy future bloom.
次第相まって高まって
Gradually coming together, rising up,
ダマッタパ和めて黒魔術
calming down with black magic.
聖の呼吸集えよ
Gather the sacred breath.
闇に震え上げるベル
A bell ringing out in the darkness.
切に響く言葉は
The words that echo earnestly are,
ブチギレ発狂パラダイス
a snapping, maddening paradise!
キラリ心底まで届け
Let it sparkle and reach deep into your heart.
これからも私の側で
From now on, stay by my side.
不思議な力撃ち放って
Unleash this mysterious power,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
and make the whole world smile!
ウラパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing 'Urapapapararira'...
一生一緒ショータイムだよね
it'll be showtime together forever, right?
暗いもの明かしてないで
Don't just keep things in the dark.
ダマッタカラダさらば踊れよ
Say goodbye to a silent body and dance!
視界外目逸らさないで
Don't look away from your peripheral vision.
今はただ離れてかないで
Just for now, don't leave me.
ヤンヤ舞ってあっち向いて
Dancing around, look over there.
今はまだ心の準備を
I'm still preparing my heart.
期待混じって高まって
Mixing with expectation, rising up,
ウラパパパ動け黒魔術
Urapapapa! Move, black magic!
我に続きごよいいよ
Follow me, it's a good night.
闇を破れ熱いよ
Break through the darkness, it's hot!
映れ希望その名は
Reflect hope; its name is...
眠りのハッショパラダイス
a sleeping paradise!
キラリ心底まで届け
Let it sparkle and reach deep into your heart.
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll make everything clear for you.
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandishing this mysterious power,
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
let's all smile together!
ウラパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing 'Urapapapararira'...
一生一緒かもね
maybe we'll be together forever.
キラリキラリと紫に染まって
Sparkling, sparkling, stained in violet...
これからもあなたの側で
from now on, I'll be by your side.
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Unleashing the magic of miracles,
咲かせる笑顔の花を
I'll make the flowers of your smiles bloom.
キラリ心底まで届け
Let it sparkle and reach deep into your heart.
これからも変わらないままで
Stay just as you are from now on.
不思議な力ほら宿して
Look, harbor this mysterious power,
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
and the world will start to smile!
ウラパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing 'Urapapapararira'...
一生一緒ショータイムだよね
it'll be showtime together forever, right?
絶対一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, for sure.
はい！というわけで メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットでしたー！
Yes! And that was Mage of Violet!
歌う前にもね 話したんだけど
I mentioned this before the song,
「世界のみんなを笑顔にする」ということで
about making everyone in the world smile...
特大魔法を使っちゃいました！
So I used my ultra-magic!
見てましたか？うらー！
Were you watching? Tada!
虹がかかって 晴天です！
A rainbow has appeared! It's a clear sky!
みんなが笑顔になってると嬉しいなと思います
I hope it made everyone smile.
というわけで 次が最後の曲になるんだけど
Well, the next song will be the last one...
その前に こうやってみんなの前で話すのも
but before that, speaking in front of you all like this...
今日が最後になると思うから
Since I think today will be the last,
お手紙を書いてきました
I wrote a letter.
では 読みます
Well, I will read it.
塩っ子のみんなへ
To all Shiokko,
いよいよ今日は卒業ライブ当日だね
it's finally the day of the graduation live, isn't it?
ギリギリの心境書きたくて 伝えたくて
I wanted to write down my feelings at the very last minute...
今日で言う昨日 卒業ライブ前日に書いて...
So I wrote this yesterday, the day before the live...
やばい もう泣いてきちゃった
Oh no, I'm already starting to cry,
まだ全然話してないのに
even though I've barely started talking.
正直まだちょっぴりふわふわしたような不思議な気持ちです
To be honest, I still feel a bit fluffy and strange.
今日卒業ライブを終えて スタジオを出たら実感するのかな
Will it sink in after I finish today and leave the studio?
家に帰ったら実感するのかな
Will it sink in when I get home?
卒業したんだって思うのかな
Will I think, 'I've graduated'?
今は悔いのないようにやり切りたいという気持ちでいっぱいです
Right now, I just want to give my all so I have no regrets.
7年目 活動期間は6年半
In my 7th year, with 6 and a half years of activity,
こんなにも長い期間をずっと一緒に歩んでくれたこと 本当にありがとう
thank you so much for walking with me for such a long time.
休止をしてたりしてたくさん待たせてしまったりして 本当にごめんなさい
I'm really sorry for making you wait during my hiatuses.
辛い思いをさせてしまったなってちょっと心残りです
I feel a bit of regret that I might have made you sad.
塩っ子のみんなに見てほしいから色んなこと頑張りたいなって思う中で
While I wanted to work hard so everyone could see me...
体調を崩してしまったり
I fell ill...
会社はどんどん大きくなってそれに適応していくのもなかなか難しくて
and the company grew so fast that it was hard to adapt.
精神面や体調は悪くなる一方で悔しかったです
My mental and physical state only worsened, and it was frustrating.
自分のことなんてどうでもいいし 壊れたらそれでいいと思ってた私ですが
I used to think I didn't matter, that it was fine if I broke down...
長い期間を経てみんなのおかげで少しでも自分を大切にしてあげたいと思うことができるようになりました
but thanks to you, I've learned to want to cherish myself.
これは普通の人にとっては当たり前のことなのかもしれないけど
This might be something normal for ordinary people,
私にとって本当にすごいことなんだよ
but for me, it's something truly amazing.
みんなのおかげです いつもたくさん愛を伝えてくれてありがとう
It's all thanks to you. Thank you for always giving me so much love.
形として届けてくれてありがとう
Thank you for sending your support in so many forms.
出会ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for meeting me.
見つけてくれてありがとう
Thank you for finding me.
心から感謝でいっぱいです
I'm filled with gratitude from the bottom of my heart.
ホロライブで過ごした思い出はずっと忘れません
I'll never forget the memories I made in Hololive.
ホロメン 支えてくれる運営さん そして塩っ子のみんなと出会えて本当に幸せでした
I was so happy to meet the Holomems, the staff, and all of you.
ずっと大好きです
I'll love you forever.
紫咲シオンは死ぬわけではありません
Murasaki Shion is not dying.
私という存在がいたこと 覚えてくれたら嬉しいなって思います
I'd be happy if you could remember that I existed.
私もみんなのこと絶対に忘れないからね
I'll never forget all of you, too.
6年半 本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for the 6 and a half years.
最強の魔法使い 紫咲シオンより
From the strongest mage, Murasaki Shion.
というわけで 昨日お手紙を書きました
So, I wrote a letter yesterday.
本当はもっと早く書こうかなって思ったんだけど
I thought about writing it sooner, actually...
どんな気持ちになってるかなと思って ギリギリで書いた方がみんなに伝わるのかなって思って
but I thought writing it at the last minute would better convey my feelings.
ギリギリに書きました
So I wrote it at the very last minute.
いや ちゃんと伝わってると嬉しいです
I hope it reached you properly.
みんなが幸せになってくれることを願ってます
I wish for everyone to be happy.
泣いちゃったよ くそー
I ended up crying, damn it.
それでは 次が最後の曲になりますが
Now then, the next one will be the last song,
ちょっとその前にお水飲んできます
but before that, I'm going to drink some water.
いや ちょっと思った通りにいかないな
Man, things aren't going quite as I expected.
というわけで
Anyway...
あ ちょっと待って
Ah, wait a second.
はい というわけで
Yes, so...
聴いてください シオン
Please listen: Shion.
シオン
作詞・作曲・編曲:じん
Shion
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Jin
真っ赤な夕空　青くなる星
The sunset sky is deep red, the stars are turning blue
心臓を焦がして　冷めない温度
Burning my heart, a temperature that won't cool down
半端に零した　声の残響と
The reverberation of a voice that spilled incompletely
半端に混ざった　花の色
The color of a flower that mixed incompletely
きっと立ち止まって　芽を伸ばしたって
Surely, even if I stood still and sprouted,
咲いた瞬間　散ってしまうのでしょう
it would scatter the moment it bloomed, wouldn't it?
いっそそれも　素敵な景色なんだって
If only I could have thought of it like that,
きっとそんな風に　思えたら良かったって
thinking it was a wonderful scene anyway.
言えない
I can't say it
「さよなら」なんて
Something like 'Goodbye'
まだ言えないまま　魔法が解けていく
The magic is breaking while I still haven't said it
バラバラになって　花になって　風に溶けていく
Falling apart, becoming a flower, melting into the wind
手を振れないまま　黙って立っている
Still not being able to wave my hand, just standing in silence
私も...
I also...
連れて すぐに
Bring me, right away
伝えたい想いを声に出したって
Even if I give voice to the feelings I want to convey
こんな言葉なんて言えないんだろう
I guess I wouldn't be able to say words like these
大事に想ってしまうから ずっと
Because I've come to cherish them so much, forever
大事なことが伝わらないんじゃないかって
Thinking that the important things might not get across
知らない 知らない
I don't know, I don't know
知りたくもないことばっかで
It's full of things I don't even want to know
胸が裂けていく
My heart is tearing apart
ズタズタになって歩くくらいは
To the point where I walk in tatters
愛しくなっていく
I'm becoming more dear
手も触れないまま 不確かにしてしまう
Leaving things uncertain, without even touching hands
ごめんね ごめんね
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
いつか時間が経ってみたら
If some time passes, and I look back
なんでもないって顔をして
With a face that says it's nothing
寂しさも 痛みすらも
The loneliness, even the pain
抜け落ちて過去になる
Will fall away and become the past
いつしか そんな日が来たら
When such a day eventually comes
そんな時が来るのなら
If such a time comes
だったら今は
Then for now...
どうしようもないくらいに 君を想っている
I'm thinking of you so much I can't help it
思い出になんてなれないくらい 君で出来ている
I'm so made of you that we can't even just be a memory
ずっと気づいていた
I knew it all along
気づいてしまったんだ
I've come to realize it
「忘れて」なんてね
Saying "forget me"...
嘘だ
Is a lie
愛しさが胸を焦がしていく
My love is burning my chest
傷になったって覚えていて
Even if it becomes a scar, please remember
忘れないでいて
Please don't forget
もう言えないから
Because I can't say it anymore
今 歌を伝う
Now, I convey it through song
笑って また会おう
Let's meet again with a smile
さよなら
Goodbye
みんな本当に、本当に めっちゃ泣いちゃった。
Everyone, really, really, I ended up crying so much.
最後まで見てくれて本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for watching until the very end.
この6年半、約7年 応援してくれてありがとう。
Thank you for supporting me for these six and a half years, almost seven years.
ずっと見てくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always watching.
ずっと愛してくれてありがとう。
Thank you for always loving me.
バイバイ！ またね！
Bye-bye! See you later!
紫咲シオン 卒業LIVE
Murasaki Shion Graduation LIVE
最大の感謝を込めて
With My Utmost Gratitude